Hello friends, I
heartily welcome all of you to SM Shala.
So there's a lot to cover, friends.  First of all let's
start with HCL technology.
Yes, we can see the numbers of HCL Tech coming in
here.
Before reading the end numbers, let's talk about dividend,
HCL Tech has
announced an interim dividend of ₹12 to its shareholders
here.  Interim dividend
means brother, you will get it instantly.  There is no
need for approval from any other shareholder here.
You can see here the record
date, everything, you will find it properly written here.
Now
friends let us come to the important thing that
how were the company's numbers?  We will go a little faster.
You can see December is the
sequence of September December.  Figures are only in crores.
So if you see the total income,
what is it at this time?  34257
crore which was in the range of ₹32,300 crore 3 months ago.
1 year ago it was in the range of ₹30,300 crore.
So you can see the income has
come from Rs 3,000 to Rs 34,000.  It came down from Rs 32,000 to Rs
34,000.  So, income revenue has been
seen increasing both quarterly and yearly here.  It's a good thing.
Then if we talk friends then
tell me what do we have to see brother?   The
expenses should not be such that brother, the income has
increased by Rs 300 and the expenses have increased by Rs 3000, then
brother, you will have to face the consequences.
So how much does it cost?  So you can see the expenditure is
around Rs 27,700 crore.  Ok?  Let
me change the screen a little.  You
might be able to see it now.  Yes 279
means 792 3 months ago 26600 and before that
ok so if we remove the expense from the income then
what will we get, if not profit then loss so if
you see here without adjustment, if
we talk about brother the company
remains in profit, the profit of HCL Tech NFT 50's big company
6465 CR is being seen without adjustment
which was 5700 3 months ago
and 6132 1 year ago.  So
you can see quarterly is a clear cut
jump.  Yearly also how much is 6132?  6465 has been
seen here.
Meaning, the quarterly and yearly profit of the company is
also looking quite good.
After this, we get to see a story changing
here.  You can see here
friends, a figure is written here,
how much?  956 crores.  What is this written
?  One Time Impact of New Labour Code.  You
all know that the government has announced new labor
codes here.  And
what is the need to do here for this thing
?  HCL Tech has to deduct
profits.  Oh, then I will have to minus it.
Meaning what will happen?  The profit can be
seen below here.  And
if you apply common sense,
what is written here?  Due to the Labour Code,
they have had to change these things.  So, are
labour codes applicable only to HCL Tech?  Yes.
This means that brother, if you see,
after this we will read the numbers of TCS.
You will see this adjustment there also.
So due to this adjustment, you can see here
friends what is happening here
that automatically the profit of HCLT has reduced from 6465 to
how much?  50509
Now there was nothing here.  So that's why it just
carried on like this.  And now if
you go to compare, what will you see
?  Let's Tax Bigs:
What is the profit for the period after deducting everything?  4082
last time 4236 and before that 4594 so from
4500 to 4000 4200 to 4000 so now
we are seeing downfall quarterly and yearly.
But why is this happening?
Because of one-time adjustment of a new
labor code.  Now if I talk about the New Labour Code,
I had made a video on it also.  To put it
in very simple words,
now new rules, laws and regulations have changed.  So
many things related to salary will have to change.
If we talk about CTC, right now you will have to
pay 50% here.  So
basically what does the company have to do now?  This
gratuity, Vachutti, PF, all the things that are there here,
now for this, some more
things will have to be kept aside here.
And that is why
we are currently getting to see this extra shock of Rs 950 crores here.
Shock
means that adjustment.  That's not XL Tech,
brother.  Everyone will have to do TCS.  We will
look at TCS numbers.  We will see there also.   So
that's why we can see it here.  The rest
of the story, brother, your profit is below.  So
your EPS will also be seen in the same direction.
EPS of 15 last time was 15.63
before that it was 16.94 so yearly quarterly it will be
seen down because
due to adjustment it has seen a decline
here.  So if we
talk about it here, you can see
what is happening in the revenue, that the actual
revenue was Rs 33872 and what was the estimate?
So you can see it is up 2%.  The revenue
is good.  But look at the profit expectation
4702 but how much did it come?  Why 4076?  It doesn't
fall that much, brother.  Yes, that is an adjustment of
around Rs 950 crore due to one adjustment.
Therefore, the profit
is seen coming down here.  So the revenue
is good but we are seeing profit mismatch.
Because of
adjustment.  You can note this down.  And
what about management commentary, there is a lot of
commentary.  But
if we talk about new bookings, then they have said that
we are seeing these things moving forward up to $3 billion.
Year on
year you can see there is a jump of 43.5%.  And
what about artificial intelligence?  So
here also he told that
we are seeing tremendous growth here.
Ok?  If we talk about CC,
you can see the performance as per Constant Currency
and he has said that he
is very confident that AI
will perform even better here and its
demand is also seen increasing here.
So HLC has shown its numbers here.
Now friends let's come to
TCS.  So if we talk about TCS, then
again they have also given dividend.
He gave two dividends, friends.
Meaning, if you check, where did the first dividend
go?  Declare the interim dividend of ₹1
plus special dividend of ₹46 has also been announced.
So if you total it, six and one is 7
and four and one is 5, then a dividend of ₹57 is
seen being given to its shareholders
here.  If you observe, TCS always
distributes dividends every quarter.  If
you look at the past track record, you will
know.  Let's come now
friends, the sequence of TCS numbers is again December
September December.   Let's
start with income first.   The
total income is Rs 68205 crore.  What was the last time
?  666 and before that the range of 65.
So if it increases from 65 to 68 then it is a jump brother.  If it becomes 66 to
68 then there is a jump here also.
We are just trying to cover things at a basic level.
Ok?  So, quarterly and
yearly jumps are visible here.  No
doubt, the component of other income remains
here too.  Even if you leave this out,
you can still see 67 65 63 so
63 67 65 67 the story is the same.  A
jump is visible in quarterly and yearly revenue from operations.
Let us see the expenses and see
what are the total expenses brother?  So 50700
49400 48500 will give income minus expenditure
profit or loss.  Now why
talk about loss, only those who have profit will talk.
So you can see the profit without
adjustment was
around 17470 last time, 17200 and
before that it was 16600, obviously it is a matter of crores
but if we are talking directly then what does 16000 to
and here 17200 to 17470 mean,
friends, the same thing is seen here that the profit of the company without adjustment is
also jumping quarterly and yearly.
And if we
reach here towards the profit before tax, then
you can see here that the
profit before tax is 14000 16000 1666. There was a
change, it fell yearly and
fell quarterly as well, so how did this happen? The
adjustment that was seen with HCL Tech,
so again, as I said, it will not be
applicable only for HCL Tech, you will see the same thing here
in TCS as well, so TCS also
told that brother, due to the new labor code, there are a lot of
differences and
they have made many more adjustments here.
He also has some things related to legal claims.
So you can see that
we are getting to see multiple exceptional items.
253 2128 than 10010
crores.  So what was the result of all these adjustments
?  The profit which was around Rs 17470 crore
came down to the range of Rs 14,000 crore.  So now that this has fallen
brother, all the mathematics in the future will be
seen falling in the same way.  So if you
pay tax according to this then it will be final if you check things here.
What will you check?  You
can see here what is the final profit after deducting everything including NPAT tax
?  10,720 crores.  3 months ago it was
12,000 plus.  Even 1 year ago it was almost
12,500.  So if you see 10 out of 12.5 and 10 out of 12, then it will
seem that there is a decline in both quarterly and yearly.
But don't forget that
due to this adjustment we are seeing this decline
here.  Ok?  Now
what EPS will you see?  That will remain the same.
Where did EPS go?  So let's see.
Look, the range was 29.45 33.  The range was 34.
34 is below 30, 33 is also below 30.
But as I told you the story, it has been a
huge adjustment.
Due to this reason, a decline has been seen here.
If we talk about revenue expectations,
you can see
what was the revenue estimate?  It was around 66.
Actually it came directly at 67, which means it slightly
beat the revenue.  But if we
talk about profit, profit was missed by 16 1/2%.  I don't
miss this much.  Yes,
why did that happen?  Because calculating exceptional items is a
very tough thing, brother.   So that's why
that profit is seen so much below
here.  Therefore,
if you read the articles, you will
see in different articles
that TCS has beaten the estimates.
But which estimate?  You
can see the revenue one here.  If you check here, let's
talk about TCS.
Revenue growth weight estimate but
we have seen the profit falling here.
This seems to be the reason behind it.
And if we talk about commentary,
especially AI, then the M of TCS
himself has said that they want to become the world's
largest AI lead technology service
company here.  You know
our company is in the service segment.  So we have to
become the world's largest AI related service company.  That's what he's saying.
Then, along with that,
how much has the annualized AI service revenue gone?  Around $1.8
billion.  And AI service revenue is
seen growing 17.3% quarter-on-quarter in a constant currency.  So that's okay.
TCS has also put forward its numbers here.
Now due to this thing,
you already know that the American market will
open at night, so we will study the ADRs of Infosys and WPRO.
Now I am making videos.  Till then
it is closed.
Those things will open as the video is uploaded.  No problem.
I'll give you guys that update in a later video.
You will get an idea of
what reaction the overall market is seeing towards these.  Ok
?  Now friends, let's come to the biggest
breaking news which has just been seen coming out.
So,
changes have been seen in the stock market holiday
and the stock
market is going to remain closed here.  A new holiday has been
added here.  On which
date?  January 15th of this week.  Yes
friends, you can watch 15th January here.   It is
written that market trading holiday 15th
January has been added.  There was only
one holiday in January, 26th, so let's
talk about today and tomorrow only.  Just yesterday
I made a video and told you that the
market is closed only on 26th January.  Now
another holiday has been added, let's talk about this Thursday, 15th January.
Why butt?  Because
if we talk about Maharashtra,
if we talk about Mumbai, then NSCBSE
is there.  So we are getting
to see elections there.  Due to Municipal Corporation
elections.  So this holiday has been officially
declared friends.  Earlier many
people were asking in the comment section, Sir, there will be a holiday on 15th.
How can I speak unless they say it officially?  Ok
?  That was a clearing related holiday but
not trading related.  But let's
end everything now.  Here we will
see everything related to the market remaining closed on 15th
January.  Ok?  So
what can you do about this point?  You can note it down and move here.
So just now we have got to see this news
here.  So okay
friends,
I have covered all the important points here.  You might find the video
helpful.  You can like and share if you want.
See you in the next video.
Bye-bye till then.